clarivate.com 2017-09-13

# Privacy statement - Clarivate

This Privacy Statement relates to the online information collection and use practices of the websites, applications and many products and services operated by Clarivate Analytics (Clarivate). We recognize that many visitors and users of our websites and applications are concerned about the information they provide to us, and how we treat that information. This Privacy Statement, which may be updated from time to time, has been developed to address those concerns.  
Clarivate is a global business with networks, databases, servers, systems, support and help desks located throughout offices around the world. The personal data you share with us will be protected by intra-group arrangements that we have put in place between all our Clarivate entities to ensure specific and adequate safeguards exist with respect to the processing of personal data when it is transferred within the Clarivate group of companies; such safeguards incorporate the standard contractual clauses as outlined by the EU Directive.

###  **Highlights**

####  **What types of personal information are collected and how is such information used?**

We may collect personal and non-personal information in various ways, including directly from an individual (for example, subscribing to a product or service, registering an account, or signing up for a newsletter), from our web server logs, and through cookies or other website tracking tools.  
We may use non-personal and/or personal information to provide a personalized website experience and deliver the most relevant and useful information, resources, and services.  
We may use or share personal and non-personal information for administrative and technical purposes such as development and testing or technical support.  
Under limited circumstances, we may share personal information with third parties.  
Clarivate uses cookies to help us optimize our website visitors’ experience and our future interactions with website visitors. For more detail, please view the Cookies and Other Tracking Tools section below, or click here to visit our [Cookie Policy](https://clarivate.com/legal/cookie-policy/).

####  **How is personal information protected?**

We have implemented reasonable and appropriate security measures to help protect personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

We use intrusion detection and virus protection software.  
Despite these security measures, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized persons will never be able to defeat them.

####  **Who else has access to personal information?**

We may disclose personal information to affiliated and non-affiliated third parties to help Clarivate with such tasks as marketing, providing technical or other customer support, enforcing the Terms of Use, meeting our contractual obligations with content and technology providers, as needed in connection with the transfer of our business assets, or reporting to law enforcement if we in good faith believe it is required by law.  
Although unlikely, Clarivate or a trusted third party may need to access personal information in connection with a digital forensic investigation of a potential security incident.

####  **How may I correct, amend, or delete my personal information?**

If you do not want your information to be used to contact you about our products and services, please see the Marketing section for instructions.  
If you uploaded, submitted, or otherwise provided personal information in connection with your use of Clarivate and you would like it corrected, revised, or deleted, please see the Marketing section for instructions on how to do so.

###  **Full Privacy Statement**

####  **What information do we collect and how do we use it?**

We may collect personal and non-personal information, including professional profile data, in various ways, including directly from an individual (for example, when subscribing to a product or service, registering an account, requesting technical assistance for a product or service, or signing up for a newsletter), from our web server logs, and through cookies or other website tracking tools.  
We may use or share personal and non-personal information for administrative and technical purposes such as website testing, development and upgrades, or technical support.  
Under limited circumstances, we may share personal information with third parties, as described in this Privacy Statement and the [Clarivate Cookie Policy](https://clarivate.com/legal/cookie-policy/). For example, we may need to share personal information with law enforcement if we believe in good faith that the law requires it.  
Please read below for more detail about the ways we collect personal and non-personal information.  
Individual-Supplied Information. If you purchase, contact us about or express interest in a Clarivate product or service, we may ask you to provide some personal information, for example, your name, professional contact details and professional credentials, such as address, position, phone number, email address. We may use this information in a contact database for future reference if needed, which may then be used as described in the Marketing section.  
If you are requesting help with technical issues, we may also ask you to provide information about your computer, computer system, and/or the issues you are trying to resolve. This information is necessary to help us answer your questions. We may record your requests and our responses for logging and quality control purposes.

####  **Web Server logs**

When you use Clarivate websites, products or services, our servers may automatically capture and save certain information electronically. These server logs include information about your device’s use of Clarivate or visits to Clarivate website(s) (“your device” may include a desktop or laptop computer, mobile device or similar device). Examples of the information collected by our servers include:

  * Your device’s Internet Protocol (IP) address
  * The name of your device’s Internet service provider
  * The city, state, and country from which your device accessed Clarivate
  * The kind of browser or device used to access Clarivate databases or a Clarivate website
  * The way your device navigates through a Clarivate database or Clarivate website
  * The date and time of usage
  * The web page from which your device arrived at our website(s)
  * The content you viewed on our website(s) and/or when using Clarivate
  * Searches/queries that you conducted via our website(s)

The information collected via web servers helps us to administer our website(s), analyze their usage, improve their content, protect content from inappropriate uses, and help our websites better operate.  
Locally Stored Data from Browsers and Devices. We may collect and store information (including personal information) locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage (including HTML 5) and application data caches.

####  **Cookies and other tracking tools**

Cookies and other website tracking tools are small text files sent to your Internet browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Since many websites rely on cookies and/or other tracking tools to help tailor an individual’s experience, most Internet browsers are initially set up to accept them. If you object to cookies or other types of tracking tools, you can review the settings of your browser for guidance on how to manage or refuse to accept cookies and other tracking mechanisms. If you choose to modify how your computer will accept cookies, please be aware that the functionality of websites or online services may be affected.

For more information about the use of cookies on the Clarivate website, please view the [Clarivate Cookie Policy](https://clarivate.com/legal/cookie-policy/).  
“Do Not Track” and Tracking Protection. Some newer Internet browsers have incorporated Do Not Track features, and when turned on, they send a signal to the websites you visit, telling the website that you do not want to be tracked while browsing. Websites differ in how they respond to these Do Not Track signals, as there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the Do Not Track signal. Because of this lack of clarity, Clarivate does not respond to the browser Do Not Track signal. Thus, most cookies will continue to be stored on your hard drive until you delete them.

 **Google Invisible reCAPTCHA**

We may use Google Invisible reCAPTCHA to secure our products and websites from abuse. Invisible reCAPTCHA collects hardware, software, and user interaction data from your device for risk analysis. reCAPTCHA data collection and use are governed by the Google Privacy Policy.

####  **How do we protect the personal information we collect?**

We have implemented reasonable and appropriate security measures to help protect your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Our Clarivate websites are protected with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. Also, we store website usage information in a data center with restricted access and appropriate monitoring, and we use a variety of technical security measures to secure your data. In addition, we use intrusion detection and virus protection software. However, please note that we cannot guarantee that unauthorized persons or technological tools will never be able to defeat our security measures.

####  **Who has access to the personal information we collect?**

Our policies require our employees, contractors and vendors to protect the confidentiality of any personal information they may access.  
We may make personal and Clarivate usage information available to all Clarivate entities and unaffiliated trusted third parties in certain situations, for example:

  * to third party agents, service providers, and/or contractors who may perform certain functions or services, for example:  
helping us promote our products and services, as described in the Marketing section;  
billing, accounts receivable/payable functions; and/or  
content acquisition and licensing services.  
to enforce our [Terms of Use](https://clarivate.com/legal/terms-of-use/);
  * to meet our obligations to content and technology providers;
  * as needed in connection with the transfer of our business assets (for example, if we are acquired by another company or if we are liquidated during bankruptcy proceedings);
  * although unlikely, a trusted third party may need to access personal information in connection with a digital forensic investigation of a potential security incident;
  * as required by law in a matter of public safety or policy, or
  * if we believe in good faith that sharing such data is necessary to protect our rights or property.

####  **Is my Information used for marketing purposes? Can I update my marketing preferences?**

Yes, your information may be used for marketing purposes. For example, we may use your information to send you newsletters, other publications, conference invitations, and/or communications about products and services that we believe may be of interest to you. We may also share your information with third party agents, service providers, and/or contractors who help us promote our products and services.  
If you do not want to receive such materials, invitations or information about our products or services, you can update your preferences at any time. Your options include updating your account via our Preference Center (where applicable), unsubscribing from all marketing emails with this form, and/or using the “unsubscribe” mechanism in the emails you receive from us.  
If you have any additional questions regarding your subscriptions or use of your information for marketing purposes, please contact the Clarivate Marketing Team.

####  **Acknowledgment of transfer**

Our websites, applications and many of our products are operated in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us may be transferred to the United States and/or third countries. We have put in place the appropriate measures to ensure that any personal information transferred from the EEA and other jurisdictions that are subject to data transfer restrictions will be adequately protected for the purposes of those rules. Such safeguards include compliance with the standard contractual clauses as outlined in the EU Directive. By using our products, websites and applications, or participating in any of our services and/or providing us with your information, you acknowledge that your personal information may be transferred to other destinations.

####  **Links**

Our websites and applications contain links to third party sites as well as to other sites owned and/or operated by Clarivate. Please be aware that Clarivate is not responsible for the privacy practices of any third party sites. Please also be aware that the privacy policies of other Clarivate sites may differ significantly from the privacy policy of our websites and applications. Therefore, we encourage our users to read the privacy statement of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to information collected by our websites and applications.

####  **Questions?**

If you have any additional questions or concerns related to this Privacy Statement and/or our practices, please contact the [Clarivate Marketing Team](http://ip-science.thomsonreuters.com/info/policy_request/?utm_source=Adwords&utm_medium=paid&utm_campaign=IPman).

####  **Changes**

If our information collection and usage practices change, we will post the changes here and notify affected customers.  
This Privacy Statement was last updated in December 2016.
